https://www.loadbalancer.org/legal/privacy-policy/

Privacy policy
This privacy policy sets out how Loadbalancer.org uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website. Loadbalancer.org are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. Loadbalancer.org may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page regularly to ensure that you are happy with any changes.
Purpose of the processing and the legal basis for the processing
In order for Loadbalancer.org to fulfil its contractual and customer obligations, there is a requirement to collect specific personally identifiable information relating to our customers. There are a couple of legal bases for the processing of such personally identifiable information; primarily personal information is processed on the basis of consent. We retain evidence of the details of consent which has been provided by our customers in order to process their information. Where consent cannot be obtained for various reasons, we may legally process the information you provide to us because we have a legitimate interest in doing so, e.g. direct marketing, on a lawful basis or for employment requirements.
Information we may collect from you and how it could be used
We may collect and process the following data about you:
– Information that you provide by filling in forms on our website which includes viewing our online demo or downloading our free trial.
– Name, address and postcode – without this we won’t know where to send your order to.
– Email address, we may contact you to ask if you have any questions or require assistance. In addition, we will also send confirmation of your orders via email and will send you informational messages as well as offers which may interest you.
– Telephone numbers – if there are any problems with your order or we need to check anything, we need to be able to contact you quickly.
– Details of your visits to our site and the resources that you access.
– If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use to improve our products and services, although you do not have to respond to them. Under no circumstances will we share your information with a third party unless legally required.
Personal data and security
Loadbalancer.org is required to transfer the personal information provided by its customers to third parties in order to fulfil contractual obligations. The following are categories of recipients that customer information could be transferred to:
– Data Centres
– Fulfilment Houses
– External IT Providers
– Payment Providers
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions are encrypted using SSL technology. We will not disclose your information to any of the relevant third parties listed above for marketing purposes.
Retention period
Loadbalancer.org retain all customer information for 5 years after they last interacted with us. Where there has been a period of 5 years and there has been no interaction between the organisation and the customer, their information is erased and securely disposed of.
Rights of data subjects
As a Data Subject (individual) which Loadbalancer.org process information on behalf of, you have the right to withdraw consent from our processing at any given time. You can do this by contacting us on marketing@loadbalancer.org. You also have a right to lodge a complaint with the Supervisory Authority (Information Commissioners Office in the UK), should you feel that we have not handled your information in line with legislative and regulatory requirements. You have the right to make a Subject Access Request to us in the event that you wish to determine what information we hold on you. We welcome these requests and aim to respond within 72 working hours of receipt. To make such requests, please contact us on marketing@loadbalancer.org. Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.
IP addresses
We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, geographic location (if you allow when prompted by your browser), operating system and browser type, for system administration. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns.
How we use cookies
A cookie is a small piece of information that is placed on your computer when you visit certain websites. Find out more about the use of cookies at www.whoishostingthis.com
We use cookies to:
– Remember when you visit this website to keep track of your browsing patterns and to build up a profile of how you and others use the website.
– Make our website work as efficiently as possible
Most browsers allow you to turn off cookies. To do this look at the “help” menu on your browser. Switching off cookies may restrict your use of the website and/or delay or affect the way in which it operates.
Marketing communications
We regularly send out email communication to keep you up to date with all the latest news and offers from Loadbalancer.org. If you wish to unsubscribe from these emails you can do so at any time by simply clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of all emails. Please note that even if you decide to unsubscribe from promotional email messages, we may still need to contact you with important transactional information related to your account and your purchases. For example, we may contact you about your account or have questions about invoices.
GDPR
The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) replaced the existing 1995 EU Data Protection Directive (European Directive 95/46/EC) on 25 May 2018. As a result of this, EU residents now have greater say over what, how, why, where, and when their personal data is used, processed, or disposed. This rule clarifies how the EU personal data laws apply. Any organization that works with EU residents’ personal data in any manner, irrespective of location, has obligations to protect the data.
How has Loadbalancer.org prepared for GDPR?
We have reviewed (and updated where necessary) all our internal processes, procedures, data systems and documentation to ensure that we are GDPR compliant. Our GDPR principles are:
– Data is processed fairly and lawfully
– Data is processed only for specified and lawful purposes
– Processed data is adequate, relevant and not excessive
– Processed data is accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date
– Data is not kept longer than necessary
– Data is processed in accordance with an individual’s consent and rights
– Data is kept secure
– Data is not transferred to countries outside of the European Economic Area (‘EEA’) without adequate protection
Activity in relation to GDPR
– Loadbalancer.org has amended its activities and associated policies and procedures as necessary in order to fully comply with GDPR following a thorough assessment.
– Loadbalancer.org has reviewed its customer and supplier contracts to ensure that GDPR compliance is met.
– Loadbalancer.org has reviewed all of its suppliers for compliance with GDPR.
– The Loadbalancer.org website and direct marketing activity has been updated so that customers have the assurance that they will be contacted and treated in accordance with GDPR requirements.
– Loadbalancer.org has maintained its accreditations that demonstrate its commitment to information security, including personal data.
GDPR Summary
Our customers’ data, and their trust, is of paramount importance to us. We will undertake our processing of data in accordance with our T&Cs and Privacy Policy, and we will always set the highest bar for ourselves in terms of data protection.
Changes to our privacy policy
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make significant changes in the way we treat your personal information, or to the Privacy Policy, we will make that clear on our websites or by email, so that you are able to review the changes. In the event that you wish to you alter your Privacy settings or opt-out, you are able to do this by emailing us on marketing@loadbalancer.org.
Contact
Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be emailed to marketing@loadbalancer.org
Thousands of deployments, all over the world
For an unbreakable solution you can truly rely on, talk to the experts. More than 15 years of experience mean we’ve encountered and solved pretty much every load balancing challenge you can think of. Thanks to this expertise, you can trust us to match the needs of your business.
Explore services
Get started
Get in touch
Start a conversation about the right solution for your business.
Get in touch
Create your quote
Transparent pricing you can see straight away.
Create your quote
Download now
Try us free for 30 days – see why our customers love us.
Download now
